I've got someone I've really respected
over the you know last couple of
quarters with his understanding of macro
and capital allocation Manish dangi of
ba AMC John just now Manish let's break
it down for our viewers here who are
trying to perhaps correlate the sell off
in the equity Market with what's
happened in
US is it a linear correlation or markets
were looking for an excuse and today
they've got
one so niik J I've shared with you a
couple of in last couple of days see
first phase of reflation trade is um
coming to an
end hello
L with Manish dangi will just get to him
in a second we've got Manus jwal as well
joining in Manus in line with the rest
of the globe although there's been a
slight bit of recovery in the US
features but having said that it's a 480
Point slide 500 points knock coming in
on the Nifty 3 and a/ qu% cut are there
any signs of a rebound coming in not
today maybe uh but later or would you
say that the pressure is going to
continue for some more time time to
come AA frankly there is no sign of
reversal till now uh but if you're
talking about uh the trend I think one
one need to be cautious because uh Nifty
has some support near to 14,500 and if
it breaks that then you may see some
more selling pressure but I don't want
to go short at current levels I think
one should wait for clarity if Nifty
sustains above 14,800 then definitely
you can create long position for the
target of around 11 15,100 otherwise is
this is no trade zone so between 14,800
and 14,500 I think it is better idea to
stay away from the
markets yeah Banks and they really are
the focal point uh having said that
you're also seeing you know weakness
across the board you can't really uh you
know get the banks to stand in U you
know outside the queue because you're
seeing L&T teken
UPL uh Tara steel OMC the entire popular
trade of metals omcs psus what have you
which actually was resilient in the last
uh one week or so when the market got a
little choppy that as well is caving in
today so in that sense there's not much
of a hiding space only maruti is lying
flat and Fallen lesser perhaps in SBI
life but I think Manish dangi is back
with us Manish we snaap the line with
you why don't you go ahead and make your
point on what we're seeing in the market
in the Bond markets
today no I'm I'm so sorry it got
disconnected um so the point I was
making is that the the the first phase
of reflation trade is sort of coming to
an end and this is sort of a phase when
um economy is in a bad condition Central
Bankers are trying to D fire uh keeping
interest rates suppressed flooding the
money flooding sort of economy with lot
of money and and so which is you know
when most of the bottom of investors you
know look atet Market with shock and all
that you know why would markets do so
well when economic conditions are bad
now that phase is starting to get over
and now what we beginning to have is a a
new sort of a tug of war I would say
between real economy and real rates
economy is actually recovered but
perversely this begins to uh sort of
take real rates higher and which is what
has happened in in last couple of weeks
um uh across the world including in us
uh Bond Ys have actually trended higher
but they've been trending higher for
last few months what unique of course in
last couple of weeks is that now not
just the inflation expectations are
rising but also real rates are rising
which is the difference between nominal
rates and break even inflation or
inflation expectation and that's an
enemy of equity or any other you know uh
long-term asset classes and which is why
I think while eventually I I think
equities would still do well but you you
sort of have a small window here for the
next couple of weeks or perhaps months
where you know there will be a struggle
between uh between real economy and real
rates Manish uh so what's the sense that
you're getting uh uh given the fact that
you were talking about that first phase
of reflationary trend coming to an end
um what is it in terms of expectations
on the interest rate front as well that
you're uh expecting because you are of
the view that we are seeing some sort of
recovery emerging in the
economy no absolutely you know I mean we
I've discussed with you folks you know
many times for last 10 11 months and you
know this vhip recovery that we've
argued many times with our investors and
with some of you has actually played out
and as I said perversely you know this
is what would is beginning to hurt
stocks in near term um now my my
long-term expectations sort of remain
same you know there's no great scarring
because of covid economy would recover
you know would continue to recover and
we we as a country and World At Large
would perhaps see one of the best growth
over next one or two years and and so
which is which arguably from from a
purely uh fundamental standpoint uh
looks super good for us at CL like
equities but in near term as I said uh
what's beginning to happen is that
interest rates are rising um and uh and
again equities and any other asset class
you know the cash flows have to be
discounted and particularly when real
rates actually begin to rise uh there
are two ways to sort of look at it it it
is possible that over next few weeks
there will be a point at which you know
fed ECB or RBI would come and say that
enough is enough and you know the
interest rate shouldn't rise and the
financial repression would be practiced
again uh the rates would be would
actually then begin to pause on unwind
and that is when perhaps you know Equity
macro would begin to open up again so in
very very near term I would say for next
few weeks and months you know perhaps
there is a little bit of a struggle uh
because while economy recovers but uh
but markets are spooked that if real
rates continue to rise then you know the
the the the discount factors would
actually stay elevated
and so to that extent you know this
popular narrative for last few years of
growth stocks you know because they
thrive in in in environment where real
rates are super low I think that would
get questioned so it's a different
narrative uh and you know perhaps you
will have to deal with it you know as it
it sort of unfolds in front of
us right fair enough um so just wanted
to get in your view just if you could
reiterate what the Outlook is when it
comes to the overall fundamentals of our
economy given that you're pretty
optimistic about the economic growth
where is it Manish that you expect that
those pain points or uh the challenges
could potentially emerge for us what do
you believe uh you know that could be
that factor that would lead to a
decisive turnaround in uh the general
undertone or trajectory of the
markets see there are two uh things you
know I I think you know economy would do
wonderfully well you know you you've
seen analysts upgrading their forecast
you know we've argued about that India
would actually do reasonably well even
in fi21 and I think most including RBI
are sort of coming around to accept that
you know growth is not as bad as they
expected it to be more importantly you
know it's very likely that in fy22 which
is next financial year you know we would
perhaps grow at 13 14% And even higher
you've seen lot of these multilateral
firms and organizations coming and
upgrading their forecast for F22 more
importantly phenomenal reforms are being
undertaken by India and I think the
trajectory is set that India would do
very very well for next couple of years
so so I actually you
know as I said the economy is very
likely to do very well not just India
but across the world but again you know
your question and you know the fact that
Nik insisted that I come and talk you
know the question we are not sort of
dealing with today is economic recovery
it's doing very well and perhaps it's
one of the reason of this perverse
reaction by market today because when
economy does very well what begins to
happen is that markets begin to reprise
real rates and uh and when they begin to
reprise real rates at higher and higher
level at some point in time you know
markets and particularly Equity markets
begin to worry whether in in some future
markets mortgages equities would be able
to adjust well with these high or
elevated real rates so so that the
adjustment process right now and which
is why sort of going back to the
original point that the reflation trades
first part is getting over I am for once
not telling that you know this is it
it's very likely that from here on the
rec recovery and the real economic
traction would actually take on the real
yeld because remember in the past for
next last many many years higher yields
have actually coincided with um you know
B Equity markets uh but intermittently
when when you know you are actually uh
phasing out from do drums as far as real
economy is concerned into sort of
relatively B condition uh markets sort
of have this conundrum whether you know
markets and economies would be able to
adjust to these High real rates so so
that's the phase we are in right now I
know a little bit complex for an regular
investor but I guess you know as I've
said many times on your show that
continue to watch macro uh inflation as
such is not not very bad if interest
rates continue to rise it's okay uh but
you
know they will induce some volatility in
equity markets and which is what is
playing out in front of us in last few
days okay um give us a sensus to where
you stand when it comes to the overall
pees and how you're looking at the
market markets from a valuation
standpoint um do you believe that as of
now uh as you had said in the past that
a lot of bottomup investors are
currently looking at those ratios and
from a historical point they believe
it's expensive where do you stand on the
overall valuation
point no I mean I've argued many times
you know value s are at least you know
especially when you are coming out of
such a traumatic experience that we've
had over last 8 10 months you know
valuations you know backward looking and
of course expensive uh it's just that
you know you have to look forward and
it's very likely that you know they will
most of these metri Price to Book or
price to equity particularly you know
would would begin to look reasonable and
you know you've seen many reports you
know from bottom up investors and you
know sales sides arguing now that look
the earnings are likely to get upgraded
quite sharply and therefore lot of these
valuation metries you know would begin
to look reasonable
uh and I I still uh think that markets
would do very well over long term uh as
I said so I I I I do not buy this point
that the valuation expensive or rather I
mean at least I don't buy this point
I've argued against the very idea that
people perpetuate that it's a bubbly
Market uh they are somewhat expensive
right now because we are coming out of a
pain a painful period of last 8 10
months of economic destruction but uh uh
you know things are looking up you know
most people on your show um most firms
are actually guiding for very good sort
of uh sales and uh profit outcome over
next couple of quarters and I think you
know they will sort of rebalance lower
um and you know valuations would
actually start to look fairly okay so
again don't look at the window of
valuation from the point of view of
today's correction and you know the
correction which might play out over
next couple of weeks it's a macro
correction playing out please understand
and you know maybe it's important to
convey to invest that it's it's not a
correction of you know high valuations
and bubbly valuations you know and
markets are you know getting unwind it's
a correction of a macro where uh you
know people are big soed today that
interest rates and real rates are rising
but the central Bankers are not putting
out fires right now uh but very soon I
think at some point in time in next one
two months at some level of US Treasury
bonds or Indian bonds you know Central
Bankers would come and dowe fire and
perhaps that is when a macro condition
for dialing thisis again would
emerge but is there a tactical way of
approaching a high inflationary
environment I mean would you want to
stay away then from rate sensitives what
we're seeing right now is a massive
coola across the board but it's Banks
which are taking the taking the sharpest
knock or would you say that
uh that's not the most prudent way uh
because you know in the cyclical
recovery Banks also are going to do well
given that they were the last ones to
actually rise up uh in the post budget
move yeah so if if you're absolutely
right that you know it's a it's a it's a
rate L uh sell off and and what does
rate hurt the most is the growth you
know I mean stocks like just think of
you know stocks like Tesla niola you
know and on Tech these are growth stocks
and therefore you know by virtue of
being growth stocks High duration okay
and therefore become extremely rate
sensitive uh whereas the other uh part
of um stuff in the stock markets which
you know almost everyone hates uh in in
last few years is the value stocks and
by virtue of being value you know
they're actually low duration stocks and
therefore uh may actually benefit from
the current U you know commodity
reflation and economic traction so so
for outright Equity investors or a
compulsive Equity investors you know it
perhaps is a time to reorient portfolios
in favor of value versus growth but but
you're right that uh that rate
sensitives would actually worsen but
then you know uh remember that banks are
different you know for banks real
economy matters and real rates you know
are not necessarily bad for banks um and
steep heeld cures are not bad for banks
so so all of these conditions are
actually good for banks and and
therefore it is true that you know today
they may be correcting I I don't track
markets you know R to R but uh in
general value including you know rate
sensitives would sorry including Banks
would perhaps to okay uh over next
couple of uh months because these
conditions are actually fairly sanguin
for
banks 22 situation actually because the
other rate sensitives as well Manish
likely you know your Autos real estate
the traditional ones I'm talking about
that's also a segment where you have
growth kicking in I mean be it real
estate on the way uh residential Market
is actually seeing bookings after
bookings or for that matter the way the
monthly Auto Sales data which is now no
more restricted to only rural Tractor
Sales but you're seeing it across the
board recovery passenger vehicles
commercial vehicles what have you
yeah so I
mean again growth is good okay and all
the time good growth is not good for
stocks and and you know different growth
conditions mean different things for
different stocks okay at least from a
macro narrative
standpoint high growth stocks typically
tend to get valued at you know at least
in last couple of years in low inflation
in deflation environment they tend to
get valued at higher multi
but then they also become extremely rate
sensitive particularly real rates again
I I I want to emphasize this there is a
little bit of an adjustment happening
right now again don't get this wrong
that you know this would also mean lower
commodity prices because uh it is
possible that good economic traction
would continue to mean that commodity
prices you know continue to stay
elevated so in a sense the some
correction that's playing out in equity
markets today is a um shall I say a
little bit of a bull market correction
you know I I hate this term but you know
it's a bull market correction because
it's happening in uh sort of a very
benign economic environment where
economy is gaining traction and it's an
adjustment of real rates which is
playing out which perhaps would actually
not last for long because in the end if
the real economy is going to do well
we've all learned over last couple of
decades that you know good economy is
good for stocks so it would sort of do
reasonably well and would mean you know
good for stocks in long term so so some
of the auto stocks uh some of the firms
you know whose cash flows are out there
in future okay and all of that was
getting priced at elevated price to
earning levels they are because you know
their grow stocks you know become
extremely sensitive to real rates and
which is why uh sort of a little bit of
shock treatment there uh because Market
has smed now how much real rates have
moved frankly it's not very high okay uh
on an average for last 5 years 10 years
us real rates let's say have been
somewhere between 35 to 50 basis point
right now they're just five basis point
so they're very low but they're coming
from minus 1% few months ago so but all
this F it was fine but right now just
markets are beginning to sort of little
get spooky about this that what if they
rise to 50 100 basis point what if fed
does not come and put out fire and so
which is why these concerns and which is
why you know some nasty Corrections
playing out but I mean again go back to
the basic theme in the end if economy
does well I mean all sorts of stocks
will continue to do very well over long
term sure I get your point U also
Marisha I'm not even sure if it's fair
to ask you but how much of a correction
would the market try and digest in this
event of the bond yield shake off I mean
we've already risen what 10% on the
Nifty uh in just the last seon series
that's the month of February and 20% on
the Nifty Bank how much could we
actually correct from here because in
the last week's correction up until
Monday we've already fallen about 5%
from the post budget
rally I mean you know more than me
actually that you know I mean bull
markets you tend to have these regular 5
10 20% Corrections over and over again
so I mean I I have no particular number
in my mind and not nor does it actually
bother me but yeah I mean it's a it's a
it's a broader thesis
and that you know broadly things will be
fine but in near term for variety of
reasons you know markets find their way
to correct and you know it's happening
how much I frankly don't know I mean but
again I just want to make this point
here that don't confuse this as an
expression of bubble going bust because
the arguments of bubble is outright
wrong why markets are correcting today
is the the logic or the reason of his
oppos oppos it of you know people like
Jeremy gram and many others have talked
about which is that it's a bubble it's
going to go bust okay it is correcting
because economy seems to doing very well
and rates are actually Rising rates are
rising and fed and many other Central
Bankers are tolerating it because even
they are uh of the view it seems that
economy is recovering very well so it's
just the opposite of you know many
people people who think that no or
pessimistic who people who think that no
it's out bad outright bad and economy
will not recover and stocks are there th
the and uh you know Sky High valuations
and will correct no the reasons are very
different and reasons are to do with
strong economy means higher rates means
some adjustment which most probably is a
temporary one how much ma'am I I I
really don't know and can't answer but
wouldn't be I mean bubbles definition of
course is you know 30 40 50% correction
and I've argued against this many times
that nothing of that sort is going to
happen uh perhaps you know this is a
good time for a lot of investors
particularly my friends and my I mean
Indians you know if there is a
reasonable correction it's it's time
that this begin to come back to us into
mutual funds and you know dial risk
because foreigners have been buying
India all along and Indians have missed
out so it's an opportunity for them to
dial risk in India
I'm tempted to ask you one more question
although I must admit that I liked how
you said it in one breath 5 10 20% but
okay uh what would you be tempted to buy
in the fall uh Banes because what
started with just an IT Pharma and
Reliance industry's kind of recovery
from the March laws has spread its wings
now all the way up to psus which is sort
of the last in the baiton to be uh
holding
up don't call psus the last one you know
it's a durable one and and again you
know I mean it's a different matter
altogether but you know absolutely
delighted to see what our government is
doing you know and I'm not batting for
government of course but you know the
whole spinoff on privatization and and
and you know government willing to exit
businesses that they've nurtured over
last 50 70 years um it's such a good
news is and I've argued with my
investors many times it's bit of a tater
moment sort of in front of us and it
seems this government's very very
committed to exit PSU so I mean I I know
you know in in a popular culture uh it
would be there'll be there'll be a
narrative that you know psus were the
last bit I think you know they're going
to be legs there because psus tend to be
both value as well as you know because
there are going to be ownership reforms
you know I think they're going to gain
traction uh and I think I would advise
investors to come in our PSU fund or any
of these PSU funds I think they're going
to do very well uh don't make this a
part of narrative that okay it started
with something and know look it it ended
with you know psus or real estate it's
not ended these are sort of part of any
bull market uh or any Market you know
that that sort of does have these
retracements you know and you've been
here in the market for so long you know
you tend to have 5 10% 15 per correction
again last 10 years if you look at Nifty
or in the first 10 years of naughties
you know you see you know in Nifty did
correct you know 10 20% time per many
times and yet your investors made
phenomenal money by staying invested so
I I guess stay invested and use this
opportunity to sort of dial risk if you
miss
this okay Manish great to have you on
the show and really you know put things
uh into perspective for us as well as
our viewers uh good speaking with you